

FRONT-END

ReactJS
EmberJS
Angular2
Ionic
BackboneJS
GraphQL
Relay
Redux
TypeScript
SASS/LESS/CSS3
HTML5
D3JS
jQuery

BACK-END

NodeJS Rails Express EJS C# & Razor Python

DATABASE

Postgress Mongo SQL

MODULE BUNDLERS

Webpack Gulp Rollup NuGet

DEV OPS

Heroku Digital Ocean IIS

TESTING

Jest Enzyme Jasmine

DEV METHODS

Agile/Scrum Clean Code Functional Code Refactor & Absract Pair Programming

UX METHODS

Rapid Prototyping Workflow Design Material Design

JILLIAN MAGSAYSAY

SENIOR FRONT-END ENGINEER

Denver/Boulder Area

www.jillianmagsaysay.com

(7) jcmagsay

(219) 776-8212

MISSION STATEMENT

As a **software engineer**, every byte of code that I touch, results in a beautiful, comprehensive, library or framework. With my extensive **front-end** experience, every design concept is taken into consideration to create a simple workflow supported by intentional color, imagery, and modern and modular atomic design patterns. With these skillsets, I can bring web pages and applications to life through creative development and design practices.

EXPERIENCE

Mondo Robot Digital Agency

07/2016 - Present

Senior Software Engineer

- Built web and mobile apps in various industries including but not limited to: Telecom/Virtual Communication, Operations Management, Healthcare Research, Science & Space Archaeology, Beer, and Cycling
- Created new project boilerplates to expedite and position projects two weeks ahead of schedule
- Efficiently working with 3rd-Parties serving up APIs, CMSs, Content Copy Documents, and other resources to saturate web and mobile applications
- Created documentation for new employee onboarding, new projects, and engineering team guidelines
- Founded and led Front-End working group to emphasize and push best practices, modern standards, and cutting edge technologies on the Engineering team
- Mentored Junior and Mid-Level Engineers in technical communication through weekly 15 minute dev chats
- Participated in several brainstorming and concept creation activities -- one of which became a profitable and billable project for a pillar client
- Consistently posting articles and blog posts in Engineering and Design team Slack channels for knowledge sharing purposes

10-4 Systems Transportation and Operations Management

11/2014 - 07/2016

Lead Front-End & Senior Full Stack Engineer

- Extensive work with Google APIs to create a real-time operational views for transportation companies/orgs
- Generated custom analytical and charting solutions using D₃ APIs
- Created several wrapper frameworks for JQWidgets, D3.js, Google Maps API, and MDL frameworks
- Assisted training teams and writing extensive documentation on Git & Git Flow after SVN migration
- Created custom 10-4 UI component library following Material Design Guidelines
- Wrote proposals, documents, and technical specification documents for new tooling and frameworks
- Extensive pair programming with Jr. Developers to teach new concepts, fundamentals, and methodologies

Markit on Demand Financial Research Web Applications

5/2013-11/2014

Web Developer, Level II

- Exclusively worked with proprietary .NET framework to create financial quotes/research websites
- Increased cross team communication between QA, Design, Dev, SQL Dev, Project Management
- Focused on creating lean code that increased performance, both on client and server
- Researched and implemented multi-threaded solutions to lazy load server-side data
- Actively participated and led development/design sync talks to close the gaps between teams
- Led and organized an Internal Tools Working Group
- Led, organized, and participated in a 20-person group participating in getting Microsoft Certification
- Created extensive documentation of all projects to ease onboarding and knowledge transfers
- Taught and mentored students in a 4 week intensive Developer University program

EDUCATION

Indiana University B.S. Informatics, Focus HCI/d & Entrepreneurship Colorado State University B.S. Information Technology

8/2009-5/2013 6/2014-10/2016

References available upon request